Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Lucile Turnbach Platt Papers, 1926-1930 RL.00739
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Lucile Turnbach Platt papers
1926-1930
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.00739
1.2 Linear Feet
900 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lucile Turnbach Platt Papers were transferred to the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) in 1987.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1891 Feb. 1 Born in Philipsburg, Pennsylvania
1910-1914 Earned A. B. from Mount Holyoke College
ca. 1916 Worked as a social worker in Rhode Island and New York
ca. 1917 Organized Hostesses, Inc., a service bureau that arranged parties, shopping, etc.
1928 May 2 Began working at JWT's New York Office in the Women's Editorial Department
1929 Jan. 1 Transferred to the JWT Personality Department
1959 Jan. 31 Retired from JWT
1963 Jan. 7 Died
For more biographical information on Lucille Turnbach Platt, see the JWT Archives Personnel Files and similar information in the Biographical Files.
Collection Overview
The papers of Lucile Turnbach Platt, former employee of the J. Walter Thompson Company's Personality Department, span the years 1926 to 1930; some Items are undated. The materials primarily document the creation of a testimonial advertising campaign for Simmons beds and boxsprings, and Beautyrest mattresses. The papers illustrate the selection of spokespersons, photographing of them and their home interiors, travel arrangements, delivery and removal of beds, and payment for their services. The materials chiefly consist of office memoranda and other correspondence among Platt, other JWT staff and product spokespersons. The collection also includes photographs and negatives, a few samples of advertisements, lists of women approached to participate, unsigned copies of contracts, and drafts of testimonials. Most of the files relate to soliciting very prominent American and foreign women to endorse Simmons products, including Eleanor Roosevelt, Mrs. Charles Crocker, Mrs. John Sargent Pillsbury, Mrs. Perry Tiffany, Mrs. Robert T. Vanderbilt, and Mrs. John W. Wanamaker III, among many others. Endorsers were paid between $1,000 and $5,000 for permission to use their names, photographs, and testimonials. Photographs of bedrooms were shot on location in the women's homes. The materials are arranged with miscellaneous Simmon's account files first, alphabetically by title, then files are arranged alphabetically by the spokesperson's name.
Mattresses; Beds; Advertising agencies -- New York; Women in advertising; Advertising campaigns; Advertising photography; Endorsements in advertising; Celebrities; Women in the advertising industry -- New York (State); Simmons Company; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; J. Walter Thompson Company; Steichen, Edward, 1879-1973; J. Walter Thompson Company. Personality department
- Alphabetical Files
  - Bed Orders, 1928-1929 and undated (Box 1)
  - Fokker, A. H. G., 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Palmer, Marion, Trip to California, 1930 and undated (Box 1)
  - Simmons Brochures, undated (Box 1)
  - Spool Beds, 1928 and undated (Box 1)
  - Women Endorsers- General, 1926-1930 and undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Women Endorsers- Lists, 1928-1929 and undated (Box 1)
  - American Woman's Association, 1928-1929 and undated (Box 1)
  - Armour, Mrs. Laurance, 1928-1930 and undated (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Mrs. Robert Low, 1927-1929 and undated (Box 1)
  - Belmont, Mrs. Morgan, 1927-1929 and undated (Box 1)
  - Biddle, Mrs. A. J. Drexel, 1927 (Box 1)
  - Cabot, Mrs. Hughs, 1927 and undated (Box 1)
  - Princess Cantacuzene, 1927 and undated (Box 1)
  - Carpenter, Mrs. John Alden, 1927-1928 and undated (Box 1)
  - Princess Chavehavadza, 1927 and undated (Box 1)
  - Choate, Miss Mabel, 1927-1929 and undated (Box 1)
  - Church, Mrs. Frederick Cameron, 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Crane, Mrs. Richard, 1927-1928 (Box 1)
  - Crocker, Mrs. Charles, 1928-1930 and undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Davis, Mrs. John W., 1927 (Box 2)
  - Dick, Mrs. William K., 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Du Pont, Amy, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Du Pont, Mrs. Henry, 1927-1929 (Box 2)
  - Fairbank, Mrs. Kellogg, 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Field, Mrs. Marshall, Jr., 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Gibson, Mrs. Charles Dana, 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Hammond, Mrs. John Hays, Jr., 1929-1930 and undated (Box 2)
  - Harriman, Mrs. J. Borden, 1927-1929 and undated (Box 2)
  - Herrick, Mrs. Parmalee, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
  - Hutton, Mrs. Edward F., 1927-1928 and undated (Box 2)
  - Jay, Mrs. William, 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Leiter, Mrs. Joseph, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
  - Linn, Mrs. Howard, 1927-1929 and undated (Box 2)
  - Mansfield, Countess Colloredo, 1928 (Box 2)
  - McCormick, Mrs. Medill, 1926-1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - McCormick, Mrs. Edith Rockefeller, 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - McCormick, Mrs. Robert, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
  - Mitchell, Mrs. J. J., 1927-1929 and undated (Box 2)
  - Morris, Mrs. Lewis Gouveneur, 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Princess Obolensky, 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Pillsbury, Mrs. John Sargentt, 1929 and undated (Box 2)
  - Roosevelt, Mrs. Franklin D., 1927-1929 (Box 2)
  - Rumsey, Mrs. Charles Carey, 1927-1928 (Box 2)
  - Sermoneta, Duchessa di, 1929 and undated (Box 2)
  - Spreckles, Mrs. Augustus, 1927-1928 and undated (Box 2)
  - Swift, Mrs. Edward F., 1927-1928 and undated (Box 2)
  - Taft, Mrs. Henry W., 1927-1928 (Box 2)
  - Tiffany, Mrs. Anne Cameron, 1927 and undated, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Tiffany, Mrs. Charles, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Tiffany, Mrs. Perry, 1929 and undated (Box 2)
  - Urban, Joseph, Room, 1929 and undated (Box 2)
  - Vanderbilt, Mrs. Robert T., 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Vanderbilt, Mrs. William K., 1927-1928 and undated (Box 2)
  - Wanamaker, Mrs. John W., III, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Warburton, Mary Brown, 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Woods, Mrs. Arthur, 1920 (Box 2)
- Oversize Materials
  - Simmons Brochures, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bacon, Mrs. Robert Low, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Belmont, Mrs. Morgan, 1927 and undated (Box 2)
  - Pillsbury, Mrs. John Sargent, undated (Box 2)
  - Sermoneta, Duchessa di, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Tiffany, Mrs. Perry, 1929 and undated (Box 2)